The Stranger
COMMISSION OF INQUIRY
ON WAR CRIMES
Leave the door open.
It's simple, let him escape!
This is quite irregular.
The repercussions could be
embarrassing.
This is a huge responsibility.
I'm sorry, Mr. Wilson, but...
Enough talk. It makes me sick!
Stop weighing the repercussions
and responsibilities.
If I fail,
I will be the one responsible.
Leave the door open,
let him escape...
This is our only chance.
Threaten me with all the fires of hell,
I maintain this position!
This trash must be destroyed!
Can you hear me?
Destroyed.
To all passengers:
Disembark immediately!
I am travelling for health reasons.
Get your passports ready.
I am traveling for health reasons.
I don't understand it.
The reason for your stay, Seniora?
I'm joining my husband.
Stephan Polanski.
What are you doing here?
I am traveling for health reasons.
What country are you from?
Poland.
Hotel el National... 7702.
You have not lost it?
Are you sure you know where it goes?
My wife is following him, he went
to the photographer's.
Probably to get a new
passport... and instructions.
I want to know where Frantz Kindler is.
There is no Frantz Kindler.
Frantz Kindler is dead and buried.
That's an order!
I have a message for Frantz Kindler.
From the almighty.
But it's forbidden.
I order you, in the name
of this authority.
Do you know his new name?
Connecticut.
This is in the United States.
The town of Harper.
Harper!
Excuse me.
- Good trip?
- Yes, thank you.
- Funny story...
- Potter?
That's me.
And you can find everything here.
Can I leave this suitcase here?
The luggage is not our responsibility.
responsibility.
Put it on the shelf,
you can take it back whenever you want.
What's the best hotel in town?
Go to the end of the street,
at Miss Peabody's.
It's that way, sir.
BOYS' SCHOOL
Can I come in?
Yes, of course.
Does Mr. Charlie Rankin live here?
Yes, but he's not here.
Are you waiting for him?
- Yes, in a few minutes.
- Will it take long?
A few minutes.
Can I wait here?
Yes, if you like.
Take a seat.
Are you a friend of Mr. Rankin?
Yes, a friend.
My name is Mary Longstreet.
He should be here any minute.
Sometimes he stays after school,
but not today.
It's our wedding day.
Are you getting married?
Yes, at 6 o'clock.
I know, it's not conventional,
but...
I wanted to put up these curtains.
Which way is he coming?
Through Webster Hall. This is the building
you see there.
What's your name?
Frantz!
- It's me Frantz!
- Meinike!
We shouldn't be seen together.
Go back to the woods.
Follow the path, I'll join you.
Hello, Professor Rankin!
- What are you doing?
- A treasure hunt.
I'm the scout.
Come on, it's ideal to lose
weight.
Come with us.
- Where?
- In the woods.
I'd like to but...
I have a lot of things to do.
Come later, we'll be back
at nightfall.
See you later.
They hanged the others,
but not me.
This man is no match for you.
You haven't changed much.
In your uniform...
you would look almost the same.
Frantz, I'm not the same anymore.
I'm not the same either.
I've changed a lot, Conrad.
I destroyed in Germany and Poland
all evidence of my identity.
Guess what I'm doing tonight at 6 o'clock?
Standing in front of a priest,
a woman at my side...
the daughter of a US Supreme Court
the daughter of a US Supreme Court Justice.
The girl is very pretty.
The camouflage is perfect.
Who would suspect that I am
the famous Frantz Kindler?
Teacher of the children of America,
so I'm hiding...
until the day we strike
again.
Would there be another war?
Of course there is.
War is an abomination.
That's why I'm here.
He released me so that
I could come and...
Who freed you?
The Almighty.
-You mean...
- God!
Frantz, I'm a new man.
You, religious!
Frantz, all the doors
were open! All of them!
It was a miracle!
They set you free so that
to lead them to me.
Were you followed?
Up to here?
- Who followed you?
- The devil!
He looks like any other man.
He dresses like us.
He even smokes a pipe!
But I still recognized him.
And I killed him.
I hit him...he died...
It had to be done.
Did you kill the man with the pipe?
The one who was following you?
Didn't anyone else follow you?
Think of your salvation!
Repent!
Proclaim your fault...
and you will be saved.
Are you really sure?
Only God can give you the strength.
Come my friend,
let's pray to God...
to give you courage.
I have offended my God.
I am not worthy of you.
Repeat after me...
I regret having sinned...
I regret having sinned.
God of mercy...
How could I have offended you?
This way, guys!
Don't let him get away!
We are gathered in the presence
of God and his faithful...
to unite this man and this woman
by the sacred bonds of marriage.
And to be faithful to him for life?
I want to.
Will you take this man
for your husband?
I do.
A wedding?
She is the daughter of Judge Longstreet,
he sits on the Supreme Court.
A tube of aspirin, please.
It's over there on the third shelf.
The cheapest one is on the left.
You have to serve yourself, sir.
There's everything you need on the shelf.
Take a look around and help yourself.
Are you at Miss Peabody's?
Just for a few days.
A coffee please.
Shall I help myself?
The coffee pot is behind the bar.
That's right, it's self-service!
What about the cream?
Here we drink it black.
This is the one on the right.
- Who is the groom?
- A school teacher.
A stranger.
I have published the banns.
I am a deputy mayor.
A game of checkers?
Deputy mayor?
Quite a responsibility!
I run the city.
We usually play for... 15... 20...
It's more like 25 cents a game.
It's expensive per point, but...
lose a little more or a little less...
Shall I start?
You must know
almost everyone here?
I know everyone!
Are you here on business?
Are you teaching?
Salesman?
Buyer ?
Antique dealer
They all come to Harper.
The judge has a nice collection.
- It's hopeless.
- He must not be a seller.
Do you have any other buyers coming in?
There's the guy from this morning.
He was on the bus with you.
He didn't come back for his suitcase.
Maybe it's one of them?
He looked more like a missionary.
He looked in the boot.
A little guy...
he looked finished and miserable.
- Did you hit your head?
- No big deal.
That's bad luck!
In this game, you can't lose your concentration.
25 cents, please.
I'm so disappointed...
Father...
Has anyone seen my husband?
Already abandoned?
Looks like it to me.
Red, have you seen Charles?
Come on, go get Charles.
He is nowhere to be found!
It's starting to get worrying.
Why, darling?
Have you changed?
Isn't it better...
to go on a honeymoon?
Give me five minutes.
Arrived in Harper
in the last 12 months.
Hello, up there.
Are you the one fixing the clock?
No, I'm cleaning it.
Very nice piece!
- My name is Wilson.
- Noah Longstreet.
I'm not sure, but...
I would say that it dates from
end of the 16th century.
Probably by Kober from Strasbourg...
the clock!
My brother-in-law will fix it.
Is he up there?
He is on his honeymoon.
He'll take care of it when he gets back.
Is he an expert?
Yes, but it's more like
his great passion.
Really! That's what I do too.
Honeymoon?
Yes, with my sister.
He has to go back on Friday
for the exams.
He is a teacher at the school.
His name is Rankin.
It's nice to show it
to a professional.
But my specialty is pewter.
It's good "Rivere",
the shape is a bit heavy.
But it's a superb work of art,
it's beautiful!
Mr. Wilson, my daughter Mary.
My son-in-law, Charles Rankin.
I wouldn't want to impose.
We are married now.
- Jeff, how are you?
- Good, you look good.
Sarah!
- It's going to get cold!
- To the table, gentlemen!
- How was the mountain?
- It was wonderful!
Mr. Wilson, sit on my right.
Jeff, in your usual place.
Charles is skiing like a champ!
I do too, don't I?
- Very, yes!
- For a beginner!
Did you tighten your knees?
Mr. Wilson makes a catalog
of Revere's works.
Mr. Wilson is an expert on clocks.
- But this is Charles' hobby!
- Your brother told me.
Are you going to fix the one in the church?
I might try.
Is it a challenge?
I hope he fails.
I like it like this,
even if it doesn't work.
How long have you been here?
Since... last Friday.
I treated you on Friday.
- How is your head?
- Much better thanks to you.
You hurt yourself on Thursday,
the day of the wedding!
Yes, that's right!...
I arrived on Thursday.
Are you hurt?
Nothing serious.
Enough to get a bump
big as an egg!
Damn door!
Your dog was very unhappy.
Here Red, to console you.
What about this meeting, Adam?
Irritating association!
- I read the report...
- Edifying, isn't it?
It's all a bunch of bullshit!
That's the way we talked in 1930, Noah.
Edifying!
This Times reporter in Berlin...
Of course he refers to rumors...
training of men,
underground meetings...
pagan rituals.
And you believe in that?
Everything is possible.
Sorry, but I think it's ridiculous.
They must be fanatics...
the majority of Germans
want peace.
You know Germany,
Mr. Rankin?
I'm sorry...
but I'm making enemies...
when I bring up the subject.
We would like the objective opinion
of an objective historian.
Only a psychiatrist is competent.
The Germans think they are
the innocent victims...
of a jealous world plotting
against them...
and led by nations
of inferior beings.
They will not admit their mistake...
It's the Germans!
We ignored Ethiopia
and Spain...
but we counted our dead
and realized what the war was.
Everywhere men
knew for whom the bell tolls.
Except in Germany!
The gods of war
accompanied them in their quest...
eyes fixed on the sword of Sigfried.
It's one of those secret meetings...
that the German dream
will come back to life...
when it will be placed, sparkling...
under the banner of the
knights.
Men are waiting for
the Messiah, but for the Germans,
the Messiah is not the prince of peace.
It's another Redbeard!
Another Hitler.
So you don't believe in the reforms
that have been taken in Germany?
I don't know...
can we change the mentality
by reforms?
The principles of equality and freedom
are not part of Germany.
All men aspire to freedom.
All men are born equal.
Liberty, equality, fraternity...
in Germany...
There is Marx!
The proletarian world has nothing to lose.
But Marx was not German,
he was a Jew.
But then, there's no solution!
Maybe there is.
Which one?
The annihilation...
the total annihilation!
I can't believe you're advocating
a Carthaginian peace.
Do I have to remind you...
that in Carthage, this regime has been
proven itself for 2000 years!
This is the answer of a pedagogue.
About teachers...
they're coming for tea on Tuesday,
do you want to come?
I'd love to, but...
my work is done here.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
Extraordinary this common passion
passion for clocks!
So Red, you like it here.
You bet!
Come on, let's go for a walk.
Honey, leave the door open,
he won't run away.
I need to walk,
I'm feeling feverish.
I will be in Washington
tomorrow afternoon.
You were right about Rankin.
He's above suspicion.
Pass me the inter...
I'd like Washington.
Only a Nazi can say that Marx
was not German, but Jewish!
I'll stay a little longer.
What's going on?
I was dreaming... about the little man.
What little man?
You know... I told you about it.
The one who came
on our wedding day.
Light me a cigarette.
What a strange dream!
He scared me!
The little man was walking alone...
in the deserted streets of the city.
When he moved,
there was a shadow.
But when he left...
his shadow stayed behind him,
spread out like a carpet.
What does this mean?
You are exhausted.
Yes, maybe.
Do you want to turn it off?
What's going on?
It looks like Red.
- What's wrong with him?
- I locked him in the basement.
Darling, what's wrong with you?
It's a dog that's never been
been locked up.
I had to.
Tonight he will sleep in the cellar.
He'll have plenty of time to play around
during the day.
Charles I don't understand
why you are holding him prisoner!
That's my dog!
Please Mary.
Is it biting around here?
Not bad. Would you like that?
I'm not equipped,
but it doesn't change anything for fishing.
I'm having bad luck today.
- Would you like some chocolate?
- I'd love some.
Does the whole family like fishing?
Dad is very good.
He's never lost a fish.
And Charles?
I call him Mr. Rankin in class.
I'm still mixing it up a bit.
He'd rather deal with the clock.
Why don't you like it?
How come?
You don't like your brother-in-law...
It's none of my business,
but I'd like to know why?
I kind of like it.
I don't see why...
I know I'm exaggerating, but...
I can't help it.
It's my job.
I hate to drag you into this but...
you're the only one I trust.
I need your help.
What do you need help with?
Your sister might be in danger.
You are an adult and can help her.
I'm not really
an antique dealer...
but more like a detective.
What should I do, Mr. Wilson?
I would like Charles' schedule
on his wedding day...
until the ceremony.
It is possible...
if Charles doesn't suspect anything...
I'll take care of him.
You must be mistaken.
Mary couldn't possibly like this kind of...
kind of person.
I hope I'm wrong, but...
everyone knows
that love is blind.
Mr. Rankin has fixed the clock.
Does it tell the right time?
And does the angel go around the bell tower?
What is the sex of the angel, Mr. Wilson?
I don't know.
Mind you, this is not important.
Do you give up?
Not at all, here's your 25 cents.
By the way, has Mr. Rankin stopped by
to get his supper?
He's been upstairs for an hour.
Yes, I know.
The days are getting shorter.
The man with the suitcase didn't show up again?
Strange.
I was tempted to look
inside.
It's not closed.
In this case,
you are entitled to do so.
- I won't open it without a witness.
- I'm here...
Dirty laundry, sweater, soap and razor...
wrapped in a towel marked:
SS Cristobel.
A pair of old shoes...
and religious pamphlets.
Mr. Potter and I have been looking
through this guy's stuff...
who left his suitcase and never picked it up.
It's been over two weeks.
Do you know what he was coming to do?
He looked in the phone book and that was it.
He looked funny...
a strange look
and big blue eyes...
and a singular walk.
He looked like he was running away.
Did he have a foreign accent?
Yes, he did.
It wasn't so much the accent,
but the way he spoke.
Would you know what happened to
Mrs. Rankin?
But no... why?
I was just trying to solve
this mystery.
Don't all foreigners have
an accent?
Mary, have you seen Red?
Not in two days.
He runs around the woods
and he doesn't even come to eat.
- He wasn't running away?
- Not until then.
That's very worrying.
Let's go home, honey.
Have you got anything new?
Your sister met Meinike
at her house.
Did Mary say so?
She was starting to do it.
She's a good girl.
She must know who her husband is.
You don't know Mary.
She won't want to hear it.
She'll find out for herself.
Do you understand?
She doesn't know anything yet...
except that she must be hiding from us
that she met Meinike.
I would like to know
the explanation he's going to give her.
I was a student in Geneva...
there was a girl...
the day before I left,
we went to the lake.
She would kill herself if I didn't marry her.
I thought it was a joke.
Of course, I was wrong...
I didn't react, she got up and...
I dove in behind her, but...
it was already too late.
Only his brother knew
that we were by the lake...
he knew that I didn't kill her
killed her, but...
he blackmailed me.
I paid and left Switzerland.
I hoped he was dead.
But on our wedding day,
he came back.
Her brother and Meinike
are the same man.
I gave him everything I had
I had...
and he left.
You should have told me...
not to keep this horrible
story to yourself.
You are a wonderful woman, Mary,
I love you.
Why didn't he take over
his business?
I guess with money,
he could afford better.
Honey, I'm extremely nervous!
I'm going to work on the clock.
Alone. It will calm me down.
You understand me, don't you?
Shall I take you home?
You don't have to.
It's late.
There's nothing to worry about here in Harper.
My poor Red!
He must have heard me whistle.
He couldn't bark.
He crawled to here,
before he died.
What did he die of?
Come on, let's find out.
This is Red, the Longstreet dog.
He looks dead!
They take him to
Dr. Lauwrence.
What could have happened to him?
A game of checkers?
You owe me money.
How long does it take
does the poison work?
Not more than a minute or two.
Red must have been poisoned
not far from where you found him.
Assessing the distance...
he had to move more and more
slowly.
Thank you very much.
Mr. Peabody, would you please bring in
these magazines?
What's the law on this kind of
of murder?
It's the same thing
as killing a man.
It's also ugly!
Four muddy legs...
no mud anywhere else.
Dry leaves with mud...
Red must have dug somewhere
in the woods.
And what for?
For a corpse, I think!
Meinike's.
The little guy?
I was just leaving.
- Any problems?
- No, I'm closing because of the search.
- What can I get you?
- Oil... What search?
For the corpse.
The police have searched half the city.
Now that's parochial news!
Which corpse is it?
The man with the suitcase, I bet.
Curious little man!
A poor bastard!
It was supposed to end badly!
15 cents for the oil.
I'll put that on your account.
Sarah told me you were here.
What's with the luggage?
Are we going somewhere?
Not us, honey...
Me!
What are you talking about?
Normally you leave your wife
when you don't love her anymore, but...
I have to leave because I love you.
You won't mind
when you know who I am.
But I married you
and that's all that matters.
Honey, for better or for worse.
Even... if I killed Red?
You couldn't have!
Was it an accident?
No, I wanted to kill him!
One murder leads to another
and then it's a spiral.
Red was scratching the grave...
of the man I killed.
Yes, your little man.
Did you kill him?
With these hands!
The same, but holding you
against me.
Now let me go.
Why did you do that?
I gave him everything, but
he wanted more.
Your father is rich.
He knew he would do anything to protect
his daughter and avoid scandal.
For a few thousand dollars...
I should have gone to the end of the world,
disappear, but...
I loved you!
I couldn't.
If we're going to run, we're going to run together!
You would do the same for me.
Who else knows that you knew
this man?
No one else.
You're the only one who knows.
Then there's nothing to fear.
No one can talk.
But Mary, if you don't talk...
you become an accomplice to murder!
But I'm already part of it...
since I belong to you.
You tremble when I touch you...
with these hands that have killed.
It's nervous.
Hold me tight, Charles!
Mr. Peabody, go inside with the sheriff,
open the coroner's office.
That's the one!
Of course, he's changed a bit.
Being buried doesn't help.
What do we do about Mary?
We can't leave her alone with him.
She'll realize that this so-called
story about Meinike is false.
I think your sister is ready
to know the truth.
Are they going to let me see the body?
I don't think so.
I wouldn't stand for it!
I've never seen a dead person... I...
How many will we be for tea?
28 in all.
You haven't touched the dinner.
It's not too much, 28
for both of you?
We'll be fine.
- We should do...
- Do what?
I don't know, I'm terrified
of all these things...
Mary, a little bit of cold blood.
You need to know exactly what
you need to say or do.
Always be natural.
Now listen to me, darling.
I'm going to turn myself in to the police.
It's your father, Miss Mary,
he wants to talk to you.
I think so.
Just a moment, I'll see.
He wants me to come and see him.
Me too?
No, just me.
It seems normal
for a father to want to see his daughter.
Okay, I'll be right there.
That's pretty strange!
Strange? No.
I'm going to the church to see the clock
while you are with your father.
You will take me back when you come back.
I'm so scared!
Why does he want to see me alone?
- He was not natural.
- Do you know what you have to say?
Is something wrong?
Mr. Wilson wants to talk to you.
Try to help him as much as you
you can.
He's going to ask you some questions.
What do you want to know, Mr. Wilson?
You know that we discovered
a dead body yesterday...
Do you know him?
No, I don't.
Did you see the body?
In this case, how do you know who he is?
how do you know who he is?
I can't be sure...
What do you suspect me of?
Of covering up for a murderer!
This picture will refresh your
your memory.
Do you recognize this man?
That's Conrad Meinike.
Commander-in-Chief
of a concentration camp.
You know him, don't you?
You saw him in Harper!
No, I've never seen this man.
Judge, would you turn that off?
I would like you to watch
this film.
I am part of the commission that
investigates and punishes war crimes.
I am tracking down the Nazis
who have fled.
That's what brought me to Harper.
I mean, don't you think...
Mr. Wilson, I've never seen a Nazi.
Who knows?
They are like everybody else...
and do like everybody else.
When it suits them.
This is the gas chamber, Miss Rankin.
They were given a shower
that would dilate the pores of the skin...
so that the gases would act
the gases to act more quickly.
And here is the quicklime...
in which hundreds of men
women and children were burned alive.
Why do I have to watch
these atrocities?
All that you have seen...
is the work of the mind
of one man.
His name is...
Frantz Kindler!
The most brilliant mind of the Nazi party.
Kindler created genocide...
for the populations of the defeated countries.
Germany wanted to become the greatest
nation in Western Europe.
Biologically speaking...
unlike Goebbels, Himmler
and the others...
Kindler had a passion
of anonymity.
The newspapers don't have any pictures
of him.
Before he disappeared...
he destroyed all tracks
linking him to his past.
Even his fingerprints.
There is no evidence of the identity
of Frantz Kindler.
Except for one small thing!
He has a hobby
that is a real passion...
clocks!
There are others...
You're the first one!
It's not over yet.
In prison, in Czechoslovakia...
a war criminal
was waiting for his execution...
Mr. Conrad Meinike,
executive officer of Frantz Kindler.
A monstrous piece of trash!
He reeked of burning flesh
on his clothes.
But we let him go, hoping that he would
hoping that he would lead us to Kindler.
He led me here...
and I lost it.
Until yesterday!
Your dog found it for me.
Unfortunately, dead and buried.
Now there is only one person left in the world
only one person left...
who can identify Frantz Kindler...
the one who knows...
formally, that Meinike
came to Harper to see him.
No, that's impossible!
Charles is not a nazi!
You were at Rankin's house the day...
- Did anyone come by?
- I don't remember.
Try it, it's been two weeks.
- No one came.
- Were you alone?
Who else was there?
Charles, he came after his classes.
He stayed for more than an hour.
There is no evidence that my husband
is Kindler.
It's just a ridiculous suspicion
ridiculous suspicions.
You want me to involve him
in this story?
You should know this...
that it's all lies!
Lies... lies!
You know that your happiness and Noah's
is more important to me than anything else.
Let's take an honest look
the situation.
Your happiness may depend
on the truth.
If Mr. Wilson is right,
you have innocently married a criminal.
Then the marriage is void!
The loyalty of a wife
is not punishable.
It is good!
He wouldn't hurt anyone except...
to protect someone he loves.
Then we'll talk to him.
Charles was not with you
that afternoon.
You told me that yourself.
You too, Adam!
You never loved him!
He's not a Nazi!
Leave us in peace!
She knows the truth.
But she won't accept it.
It's so horrible!
What she can't accept...
is that she could give
her love to such a monster.
But we have an ally!
Her subconscious.
He knows the truth, he will fight for it.
The desire for truth in your daughter
will prevail.
If he is not Charles Rankin,
we should be able to prove it easily.
Let him not be Charles Rankin,
I don't care!
What you have to prove,
is that he is Frantz Kindler.
What are you going to do?
For your daughter...
I think she's going to have
a breakdown.
Logical result of the conflict
that haunts her.
- Rankin is going to find out.
- So what?
He won't be able to trust her anymore.
He will have to act.
He may run away.
This does not prove his guilt.
Or else...
- Keep going!
- He'll kill her!
I understand that you are shocked,
you are her father.
That's why I'm talking to you
I'm talking to you frankly.
Of course, we'll try
to prevent this crime.
However, an attempted murder
would be the best possible evidence.
Listen...It works!
after a hundred years!
It was a trap!
Mr. Wilson was there.
He claimed you were a Nazi...
and that I should believe him!
He is very clever!
He wanted to terrorize me with that corpse.
Who does he think I am?
A Nazi! Frantz Kindler!
They tried to trap me...
but I didn't say anything.
They couldn't believe it!
Will you be able to prove
that you're not... a Nazi?
We'll find someone who was with you.
If you're right, there's nothing he can do.
There is no danger...
if you don't talk.
Of course not!
Even under torture,
I wouldn't talk!
The chimes have woken up all of Harper.
We have to go down to greet them.
Let's look natural.
You have to smile.
Will that do?
Let's go downstairs, honey.
The chime rings
and the angel took flight again...
Professor, I take my hat off to you.
Congratulations, Mr. Rankin!
The rector will be delighted!
We'll make it, honey.
Your roosters will crow every quarter
every quarter of an hour tonight!
Sarah, I told you to draw the curtains!
I don't want sunlight, it spoils them.
That's ridiculous and you know it.
In my father's house you didn't do that.
This is my house,
I want them pulled!
As you wish.
Are you ready for the reception?
It's already time.
Did you open the grave?
Was it horrible?
Quite unpleasant!
Another modern prescription!
Sleeping pills are not good!
A dollar 65.
Shall I wrap them up?
Don't overdo it!
A man who does his job
sleeps well at night.
It's because of the clock!
My wife ordered an ice cream.
Someone who was going to your house
took it away.
Mr. Wilson.
I never go out alone anymore.
The murderer is still at large...
I hope you haven't
forgot to invite me.
Of course I didn't.
Mr. Potter gave me this for you.
The ice cream, Sarah is waiting for it.
I hope it hasn't melted!
I'm not holding you back any longer.
Would you like a drink?
- Do you know Dr. Hippard?
- Sure, how are you?
Grandma, do you want anything?
Nothing, I have everything I need.
- Where is Rankin?
- He'll be here any minute.
His work on the clock
is remarkable.
What was the name of this Frenchman?
Landru!
Maybe there are other graves
in the woods...
What is Emerson's phrase
about this crime?
Please excuse my tardiness.
Do you know this quote
by Emerson?
"A crime is committed and everything freezes."
No, it doesn't.
A crime is committed
and the earth is crystal.
A crime has been committed... I'm there!
The coat of the snowman
of snow on the ground...
which resounds with all the noises
of the animals in the forest.
We can't remember the words.
We can't erase
all traces.
Even if it's far from the ground,
evidence will reveal the crime.
Do you know that you are
our number one suspect.
We think you killed to get
to get hold of rare antiques...
Why did you fix the clock?
Harper was so quiet before.
- What is Wilson doing here?
- I don't know.
- You invited him! What is he looking for?
- Are you feeling well?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Can I help you?
It broke,
the beads scattered on the floor.
They went up.
When I left,
she was still crying.
She's falling apart.
Her subconscious has almost won.
Now we have to watch her
very closely.
I always have to know where she's going.
If she doesn't tell you anything, you have to keep her
on any pretext.
Is that understood, Sarah?
By breaking her necklace,
she signed her death warrant.
Her life is in our hands.
Every time she walks
on a slippery place...
or near something
that can fall...
driving a car, anything that could result in a
could result in a fatal accident...
his life is in danger!
Not with me!
Today, we will try to finish with the
with the reign of Frederick the Great.
King of Prussia, Count of Brandenburg,
prince of Poland...
On the 18th... Harper.
Mary, it's Charles.
I can't talk any louder,
so listen carefully...
Something very important
has happened.
Come to the church immediately.
No one must know where you are going.
Don't tell anyone. Park your car
behind the church, near the door.
Put it there with the rest.
What's that, Mr. Peabody?
Are you going out?
Where are you going?
I ask you where are you going?
I heard you.
Sarah, I'm not a child anymore,
I'm married!
Not for a long time!
I'm in a hurry!
That's no reason to ignore me!
- What is it, Sarah?
- Well...I...
Tell me what's going on?
I don't know what's going on with you...
you didn't talk to me
in that tone before.
I'm useless here!
I am old.
If you want me to leave...
This is all nonsense!
I'm going to pack my suitcase and leave.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
I can't do without you.
- Is that right?
- Yes, it's true.
You will never leave me.
You know I love you...
like my own daughter.
I have to go, I promised.
But where?
That's enough, Sarah!
It's a secret.
What's going on?
My heart... I can't breathe! It hurts!
Don't move.
The 1-3-0 please.
I was supposed to join Charles
in the bell tower, but I can't...
can you tell him to wait for me?
Noah, please don't tell anyone!
It's important.
Let me speak to Mr. Wilson.
Looks like it's going to snow.
It's getting late, ladies,
you are working too hard.
No, Mr Rankin. We closed
as usual at 3:30.
That's right.
I finished 10 minutes early.
It's 3:44.
I was playing checkers,
how time flies!
How distracted you can be!
This is your lucky day!
- I can't find them!
- What?
- The headbands.
- Next to the mufflers.
Can you help me?
They are in their place, in the box.
4:00, leave Potter
4:05 at my place.
Everything increases!
Do you take this?
You're setting a bad example for me.
I didn't want to stay that long.
What about my revenge?
It's your turn.
He's moved on.
You can still smell the glue.
Look, it's going to snow.
That's it, Professor.
Double or nothing?
Good afternoon.
Didn't you go to church?
She had like a... a stroke.
Jeff asked me to look after her.
- But what's going on?
- Nothing's happening...
Why this meeting at the church?
- You said it was important.
- Nothing is important...
I failed...
out of caution.
Explain yourself!
Excuse me.
I'm not feeling well.
I'm allowed to break down too.
I'll explain in due course.
Anything new?
Nobody will find anything, as long as...
I haven't left my room.
We're talking about arrest!
I have a headache.
The necklace episode worried me.
I thought you had talked to your father.
You have nothing to worry about.
What did you say to Noah?
About what?
- Did you see it?
- No, why?
- Did you come straight from church?
- Is this an interrogation?
I couldn't come, so I asked
Noah to let you know.
You didn't have to!
- Call him back right away!
- It is impossible!
- Call him back!
- He's gone!
If he dies, you will be responsible!
You have ruined everything!
It could have worked...
but you were there the day that...
And you tell Noah!
I didn't kill Noah!
Yes, you did, if he climbs the bell tower ladder!
You wanted to kill me!
Yes, it's you!...
Frantz Kindler!
Kill me... I want to!
I have nothing to live for,
now.
Kill me, but don't touch me!
Take this!
Give me the police.
The barricades are ready.
We're watching the station.
He's not in the woods.
- I'm going in.
- I'm going to the police.
Capturing him should be easy.
We'll try to get him alive.
She's gone.
She's not in the house anymore!
The bell tower!
I don't know.
If he's there and if she gets there before us...
What are we going to do?
Call the captain,
we need backup.
To the church, quickly!
Don't move! I am armed.
No need, I am alone.
What are you doing here?
Help me upstairs.
Are you telling the truth?
Why would I lie?
Were you followed?
I went through the cemetery,
nobody saw me.
I wanted you to let me come up here.
- What do you want?
- I came to kill you.
You are the one who is going to die!
You had to fall off that ladder.
You're going to fall...
I don't care if you fall with me.
You are stupid.
They searched the woods.
A real anthill!
I had to run away to be sure...
They'll know you killed me.
You're on the verge of a breakdown...
and you broke down.
Why else would you be here?
In an empty church, in the middle of the night!
We will conclude to suicide...
No need to kill her!
It won't do any good.
Look out the window!
Look out!
This is a trick! A lousy trick!
Stuff!
That's all you know!
I don't need it.
You won't need them anymore.
You're finished, Frantz Kindler!
Harper's citizens,
they're coming to get you.
All those you were laughing at,
you won't fool them anymore!
You can kill me and Mary
and half these people,
but there's no way out.
You were already down to Harper.
And now this bell tower
which is closing in on you.
Everything they say is wrong!
I obeyed the orders.
You were giving them!
I did my duty.
Don't turn me in,
I am not a criminal!
You are.
Give me that gun!
Mary is safe, Mr. Wilson,
we're going to help you.
No, I'm all right.
- What happened?
- We won.
What?
You're going downstairs?
I want a new ladder.
Broken ankle, cracked skull...
That's enough!
I'm not taking any more risks!
We understand you well,
Mr. Wilson,
don't worry,
you won't have any more problems.
Have sweet dreams!
BF-WATCH TV 2021